activityvillage.co.uk 2017-05-09

# Privacy Policy

We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm and continuing commitment to the privacy of personal information provided by those visiting and interacting with this web site. We hold the privacy of your personal information in the highest regard. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.

We recognise the importance of protecting your privacy and our policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site. This policy will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers' needs.

### Your Consent

By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at any time with or without notice.

### What Information Do We Collect?

When you visit this web site you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis, and Website use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Website.

1\. Personal Information You Choose to Provide

Registration Information: If you register for any of our products, services or newsletters you will provide us information about yourself.

Email Information: If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.

2\. Website Use Information

Similar to other websites, this website utilises a standard technology called "cookies" (see explanation below, "What Are Cookies?") and web server log files to collect information about how our Website is used. Information gathered through cookies and web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at this website, and the websites visited just before and just after this one.

In addition, third parties may be placing and reading cookies on your browser, or using web beacons to collect information, in the course of ads being served on this website.

Log Files: As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

Cookies and Web Beacons: We may use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. Their use may allow us, for example, to show you only one popup per visit.

Advertisements: We may also use third party advertisements to support this site. Some of our advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing UK-based ads to someone in the UK, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit this website. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [ click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

DoubleClick DART cookies: We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history. DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting [ http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx).

Videos:On some pages in this website we showcase YouTube videos. If you watch one of these videos, YouTube may store cookies in order to track how people are watching videos.

3\. How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?

Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing the products and services you requested, to monitor the use of the service, our marketing and promotional efforts and improve our content and service offerings, and customize our site's content, layout, services and for other lawful purposes. These uses improve our site and better tailor it to meet your needs.

Furthermore, such information may be shared with others on an aggregate basis. Personally identifiable information or business information will not be shared with parties except as required by law.

Occasionally, if you have opted into a newsletter we may provide, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our website, new services, and special offers we think you will find valuable. You may notify us at any time if you do not wish to receive these offers by emailing us at the link provided on the newsletter.

4\. What Are Cookies?

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a Website, that site's computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each Website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a Website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Browsers are usually set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you may alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our site will not function as effectively when viewed by the users. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive or pass on computer viruses.

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

You can read more about cookies and find detailed information for managing your cookies here:  

More information about cookies from the UK government:  

5\. How Do We Use Information We Collect from Cookies?

As you visit and browse this website, the site uses cookies to differentiate you from other users. In some cases, we also use cookies to prevent you from having to log in more than is necessary for security. Cookies, in conjunction with our web server's log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our website and which parts of the site are most popular. This helps us gather feedback to constantly improve our website and better serve our clients.

We make use of a tool from Google called Google Analytics. The Google Analytics software is described [here](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html). To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not intentionally store any personal information that your browser provided to us in your cookies.

There is more information about Cookies below.

6\. IP Addresses

IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as traffic data so that data (such as the web pages you request) can be sent to you.

7\. Sharing and Selling Information

We do not share, sell, lend or lease any of the information that uniquely identify a subscriber (such as email addresses or personal details) with anyone except to the extent it is necessary to process transactions or provide services that you have requested.

8\. What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights. We may also disclose account information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms of Use or to protect the safety of our users and the Public.

9\. What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Website?

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website or the information or content contained therein. Often links to other websites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our website.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including web sites, which have a link on our Website, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

10\. Newsletter Opt-in and Opt-out

It is easy for newsletter subscribers to unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time that they will not receive future messages. After unsubscribing we will discontinue sending the particular messages as soon as technically feasible.

11\. A Special Note About Children

ActivityVillage.co.uk is not aimed at children, but rather their parents, carers and teachers. Children are not eligible to use our services unsupervised and we ask that children (under the age of 13) do not submit any personal information to us. If you are under the age of 13, you can use this service only in conjunction with permission and guidance from your parents or guardians.

12\. Acquisition or Changes in Ownership

In the event that the web site (or a substantial portion of its assets) is acquired, your information would be considered part of those assets, and may be part of those assets that are transferred.

13\. Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If/when changes are made to this privacy policy, we may email users who have given us permission to do so. We will post any changes here, so you may want to check back periodically. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the future, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, without your prior consent.

### Pertaining to Purchases from Activity Village Shop ("our shop")

When you purchase something from Activity Village Shop, including Activity Village Membership, as part of the buying and selling process, we collect the personal information you give us such as your name, address and email address.

When you browse our shop, we also automatically receive your computer’s internet protocol (IP) address in order to provide us with information that helps us learn about your browser and operating system.

Email marketing (if applicable): With your permission, we may send you emails about our store, new products and other updates.

A. How do you get my consent?

When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only.

If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, like marketing, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent, or provide you with an opportunity to say no.

B. How do I withdraw my consent?

If after you opt-in, you change your mind, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at anytime, by contacting us here.

C. Disclosure

We may disclose your personal information if we are required by law to do so or if you violate our Terms of Service.

D. Shopify

Our store is hosted on Shopify Inc. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you.

Your data is stored through Shopify’s data storage, databases and the general Shopify application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall.

Payment: If you choose a direct payment gateway to complete your purchase, then Shopify stores your credit card data. It is encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is stored only as long as is necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After that is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted.

All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of credit card information by our store and its service providers.

For more insight, you may also want to read Shopify’s Terms of Service or Privacy Statement.

E. Third-party providers

In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.

However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions.

For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.

In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.

As an example, if you are located in Canada and your transaction is processed by a payment gateway located in the United States, then your personal information used in completing that transaction may be subject to disclosure under United States legislation, including the Patriot Act.

Once you leave our store’s website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service.

F. Security

To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption. Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.

G. Cookies

Here is a list of cookies that we use. We’ve listed them here so you that you can choose if you want to opt-out of cookies or not.

_session_id, unique token, sessional, Allows Shopify to store information about your session (referrer, landing page, etc).

_shopify_visit, no data held, Persistent for 30 minutes from the last visit, Used by our website provider’s internal stats tracker to record the number of visits

_shopify_uniq, no data held, expires midnight (relative to the visitor) of the next day, Counts the number of visits to a store by a single customer.

cart, unique token, persistent for 2 weeks, Stores information about the contents of your cart.

_secure_session_id, unique token, sessional

storefront_digest, unique token, indefinite If the shop has a password, this is used to determine if the current visitor has access.

H. By using our shop, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.

I. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

J. If our store is acquired or merged with another company, your information may be transferred to the new owners so that we may continue to sell products to you.
